American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIc. 1826-1836 APS.Archives.IIc APS.Archives.IIc
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, July 30, 1834; 10x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Arago. 1p. and add.: D.B. Warden end. In French. Thanks for publications.
  - books and tracts sent to Jacob Snider to bind, August 4-August 5, 1834; 7 13/16" x 12 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. D.
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to William Zollickoffer, August 17, 1834; 7 11/16" x 9 3/4"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. Copy of L.S. Regarding the inferior quality of silk produced by worms fed exclusively upon lettuce. The Society cannot sponsor such a project.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 28, 1834; 10x8; École nationale supérieure des mines de Paris
    Paris, L.S.: LePlay. 1p.and end. In French. Forwards publications. On same sheet is letter from Vaughan to LePlay; Dec.29 [1834].
  - Letter to Mr. [D.B.] Warden, Aug. 28, 1834; 8x5; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Cardot. 1p. and add. In French. Asks him to forward publication to the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 29, 1834; 8x5; Nulty, Eugenius
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards publication by Duhamel.
  - [William Pettis?] to John Vaughan, August 29, 1834; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Pettis, William
    Baltimore, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Inquires whether a paper on "The natural history of the cicada septemdum" would be acceptable for A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Prevailing winds and state of the thermometer at Fort Union, 1834 Sept. 1 to 1835 August 31; 7 7/8" X 9 3/4"; Hamilton, C.J.A.
    Scope ane Contents note
    Chart of prevailing winds and thermometer readings at Fort Union at the mouth of the Yellow Stone river from 1834 Sept. 1 to 1835 August 31. From t.p., 12 pp. Com. Presented to A.P.S.: November 4, 1836. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 693.
  - D. B. Warden to ---- Bertrand, September 2, 1834; 4 1/2" x 6 7/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. 3d. Per N. Unsigned. (In French.) Requests Bertrand to forward a volume of the Institute [of France] and some miscellaneous material to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 3, 1834; 10x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards volumes.
  - Letter to J[oh]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 16, 1834; 10x8; Hollandsche Maatschappij der Wetenschappen
    Philadelphia; Haarlem, L.S.: M. V. Marum. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Forwards volumes.
  - Report of committee on paper by Nulty, Sept. 19, 1834; 8x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: A.D.Bache and B.H.Coates. 2p.and end. Refers to Franklin's magic circle. Cf. Minutes, p.657. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 205 ff. FILM54-66 FRAME109
  - Letter to [Peter S.] Du Ponceau, Philadelphia, Sept. 23, 1834; 10x8; Martini, Adriano
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and end. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Sept. 25, 1834; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edw[ar]d. T. Bennett. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - [Marmaduke] Burrough to the Amer[ican] Philosophical Society, October 2, 1834; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Burrough, Marmaduke
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. 3d. per. L. Unsigned. Presents seeds and coins from India to the A.P.S. See Minutes, oct. 3, 1834, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 657.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Oct. 3, 1834; 10x8; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Peter Clare. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, Oct. 7, 1834; 9x7-1/2; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
  - Letter to Richard Harlan, Philadelphia, Oct. 16, 1834; 9-1/2x8; Forstall Bros. & Berthoud
    New York, A.L.S.: Sims Atterbury. 1p.and add. Received casts of fossils for the American philosophical society.
  - List of 101 brass and copper coins and medals presented to the American Philosophical Society by Joshua F[rancis] Fisher, October 17, 1834; 7 5/8" x 12 1/2"; Fisher, Joshua Francis, 1807-1873
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D. Unsigned. See Minutes, October 17, 1834, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 659. RECATALOGED 7 Jan. 1981 now under APS. Report of Committee on JFF's gift of 101 brass...
  - Letter to William Vaughan, 1834 October 20; London Institution
    Seeks acknowledgement from the A.P.S. for the "last part" of Vol. IV of the Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 24, 1834; 9-1/2x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards volumes.by Charles Babbage.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, London, Oct. 27, 1834; 10x8; Royal Irish Academy
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jos.H. Singer. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Papers pertaining to the furnishings for Philosophical Hall, 1834 October 27- 1847 April 21; American Philosophical Society.
    Receipts for furninshings for Philosophical Hall.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Nov. 6, 1834; 12x8; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edw[ar]d Turner. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Catalogue of plaster casts and fossil specimens sent to Dr. [Richard] Harlan for the [American] Philosophical Society., November 7, 1834; 7 1/4" x 9 3/8"; Muséum national d'historie naturelle (France)
    Presented, 3 pp. and endorsements. D. (In French.)
  - Joseph Henry to John Vaughan, November 17, 1834; 8" x 9 7/8"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Princeton, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Mr. Alexander leaving for Georgia to observe eclipse. Results to be communicated to the A.P.S. FILM 235 FRAME 2
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 19, 1834; 10x8; Worcester, Joseph E. (Joseph Emerson), 1784-1865
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Presents volume.
  - Report of committee on [A.D.] Bache's paper on the magnetic dip, Nov. 21, 1834; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Ch[arle]s N. Bancker, Isaiah Lukens and Thos. McEuen. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.660. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 209ff.
  - Report of committee on plants given to the society by Dr. Short, Nov. 21, 1834; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: R.Eglesfeld Griffith, Charles Pickering, and Richard Harlan. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.660.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 21, 1834; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Nich.Carlisle 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to W[illia]m Vaughan, London, Nov. 22, 1834; 9x7-1/2; Bath and West and Southern Counties Society
    A.L.S.: B. Leigh Lye. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1834 Nov. 22; Anderson, Henry James
    Reports receipt of the latest issue of the Transactions.
  - Receipt to the American philosophical society for engraving of insects, Nov., 1834; 4-1/2x8; Welch, Thomas B., 1814-1874
    D.S. 1p.
  - Annual report... Philadelphia, December 5, 1834; 8" x 9 1/2"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on publications
    5 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Franklin Bache, Isaac Lea, R[obert] Eglesfeld Griffith.
  - List of four silver and nine copper coins presented to the American Philosophical Society by Joshua F[rancis] Fisher, December 5, 1834; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Fisher, Joshua Francis, 1807-1873
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D. Unsigned. See Minutes, December 5, 1834, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 661.
  - E[ugenius] Nulty to John Vaughan, December 8, 1834; 7 3/4" x 9 13/16"; Nulty, Eugenius
    New York, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Relative to his communication to the A.P.S. on Franklin's magic square.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 16, 1834; 10x8; Catullo, Tommaso Antonio, 1782-1869
    Padua, L.S. 1p. and end. In Italian. ----English translation. Forwards volumes.
  - E[ugenius] Nulty to John Vaughan, December 17, 1834; 7 7/8" x 10 1/8"; Nulty, Eugenius
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Submits title for his paper in the A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 18, 1834; 12-1/2x8; Geological Society of London
  - Memorandum of stocks purchased from the Magellanic, etc. funds for the American philosophical society, Dec. 18, 1834; 8x6-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Annual report... Philadelphia, December 19, 1834; 8 1/8" x 13 3/8"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on finance
    1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Clement C. Biddle, Roberts Vaux, George Ord.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Dec. 20, 1834; 10x8; Zecchinelli, Gio. Maria (Giovanni Maria), 1776-1841
    Padua, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In Italian. ----English translation.by DuPonceau. Thanks for election and forwards publications.
  - Report of the committee appointed to examine the historical and literary documents in the possession of the A.P.S., and to report... which of them it might be expedient to publish... [Philadelphia], December 26, 1834; 7 13/16" x 9 15/16"; American Philosophical Society. Historical and literary committee
    6 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau, J[oshua] Francis Fisher, J[oh]n Vaughan.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 26, 1834; 9x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards volumes.from the horticultural society.
  - Letter to Alex[ande]r Eyriés, [freres], Le Havre, Dec.29, 1834; 7x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Forwards APS publication to Paris. On same sheet as letter from Vaughan to Geo. Dickey; Dec. 29, 1834.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Dickey, Dec. 29, 1834; 7x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.L. 1p. Forwards material. On same sheet is letter from Vaughan to Alexander Eyriés, freres; Dec.29,1834.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 30, 1834; 12x8; Royal Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Chas. Konig. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for money to be paid to David Bailie Warden, Dec., 1834; 5x7-1/2; Dobson, Judah
  - List of names and amounts paid, , 1834-1835; 4 7/8" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 4 pp. D. Appears to be a list of members of the A.P.S. who paid their dues.
  - Report of committee on the publication of death notices, Jan. 2, 1835; 9x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: J.K.Kane, W.H.Keating and Ch.D.Meigs. 1p. Cf. Minutes, p.663.
  - Edward H. Courtenay to Cha[rle]s D. Meigs, January 3, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Courtenay, Edward Henry, 1803-1853
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 5, 1835; 10x8; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Friendly letter. Forwards publications to the American philosophical society
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 9, 1835; 8x6-1/2; Biddle, Clement C. (Clement Cornell), 1784-1855
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning investments for the American philosophical society.
  - James Ferguson to John Vaughan, January 9, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Ferguson, James, 1797-1867
    Washington, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Wishes to borrow the plates that accompanied [F. R.] Hassler's papers on the survey of the coast, as the work is to be reprinted.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Athenaeum, Jan. 9, 1835; 9x7-1/5; Hans, R., Jr.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Wants new stove in his office.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 9, 1835; 6x8; Sargeant, John
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Makes payment to the American philosophical society for 1835.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 10, 1835; 10x8; Julius, N. H. (Nicolaus Heinrich), 1783-1862
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Presents volume.
  - Recommendation to the A.P.S., Jan. 15, 1835; 9-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society. Historical and literary committee
    D.S.: J. Francis Fisher. 1p. and end. Suggests that the Historical society of Pennsylvania be allowed to copy certain manuscripts in the library. Cf. Minutes, p. 664.
  - Report of committee on Chevalier Morelli's paper, Jan. 16, 1835; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau, J.Francis Fisher and Jn. Vaughan. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.664.
  - C. W. Short to Ch[arles] D. Meigs, January 18, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Short, CCharles Wilkins, 1794-1863
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Lexington, Kentucky, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - E[ugenius] Nulty to John Vaughan, January 19, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Nulty, Eugenius
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Declines election as an officer of the A.P.S. Concerning the proofs of his article.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 20, 1835; 10x8; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Calcutta, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Prinsep. 1p.and add. Thanks for publication. Refers to mastodon.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 23, 1835; 10x8; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Calcutta, L.S.: Prinsep. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications.
  - James Ferguson to John Vaughan, January 28, 1835; 8" x 9 7/8"; Ferguson, James, 1797-1867
    Albany, N. Y., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Concerning the use of plates in the possession of the A.P.S. for a reprint of F. R. Hassler's work on the coast survey.
  - Joseph Henry to John Vaughan, January, 1835; 8'' x 9 15/16''; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    --, Princeton, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Returns thanks for his election to membership in the A.P.S. Intends to communicate some results of his work at the next meeting. FILM 235 FRAME 3
  - Biographical memoir of the late Thomas Say Esqr. read before the Philosophical Society of Pennsylvania, 1835 January; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    A biogrphical memior read before the A.P.S. by George Ord in January 1835 after Thomas Say's death.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughn, Feb. 1, 1835; 8-1/2x6; Real Academia de la Historia
    Madrid, L.S.: Vicente Gonzalez Arzao. 3p.and end. In Spanish. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, Feb. 2, 1835; 9-1/2x8; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    Adelphi, L.S.: Arthur Aikin. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publication.
  - Christopher Columbus Baldwin to John Vaughan, February 3, 1835; 8 1/8" x 9 7/8"; Baldwin, Christopher Columbus, 1800-1835
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Worcester, Mass., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. The librarian of the American Antiquarian Society arranges for an exchange of duplicate pamphlets with the A.P.S.
  - Edw[ard] Livingston to ----, February 3, 1835; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Livingston, Edward, 1764-1836
    Paris, 2 pp. A.L.S. will be pleased to transmit communications to and from the Society. Low price of old editions of French books.
  - Henry Ja[me]s Anderson to John Vaughan, February 5, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Anderson, Henry J. (Henry James), 1799-1875
    New York, 1p., address and endorsement. Requests loan of Memoris of American Academy of Arts and Sciences, n.s., I.
  - Agreement of the committee on the insurance of the property of the Am[erican] Phil[osophical] Society, February 6, 1835; 6 5/8" x 8 1/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsements. D.S.: Roberts Vaux. Books, $16,000; cabinet of minerals, $4,000; building, $5,000.
  - Report of committee on [Joseph] Henry's article on electricity, Feb. 7, 1835; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: A.D.Bache and Rob[er]t Hare. 1p. and end. Cf. Minutes, p.666. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 217 ff.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 10, 1835; 10x8; Wharton, Thomas I. (Thomas Isaac), 1791-1856
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning property which is about to be mortgaged to the society.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, February 10, 1835; 6 7/8" x 8 13/16"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. With regard to the exchange of various books and journals.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Feb. 17, 1835; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 18, 1835; 9-1/2x8; London Institution
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: E. W. Brayley 1p.and add.,end. Thansk for publication forwarded by W. Vaughan.
  - Report of committee on Professor Henry's paper on electricity, Feb. 20, 1835; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: A.D.Bache, Robt. Hare and Franklin Bache. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.666. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 223 ff.
  - Report... Philadelphia, February 20, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on publications
    2 pp. D.S.: Isaac Lea, Isaac Hays. In re papers ordered to be printed; state of finances of the committee.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Feb. 20, 1835; 10x8; Royal Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Chas.Konig. 1p.and end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 20, 1835; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1835 February 20; Quadrada, F. de P.
    Reports that he had presented the books and papers of the A.P.S. to the Royal Acadamy. Also he says that Dr. Chapman and Judge Hopkinson have been appointed members of the Academy of History.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 23, 1835; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Forwards publications.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 24, 1835; 10-1/2x8; Eyriès, Alexandre
    Havre, A.L.S. 1p.,end.and end. In French. Receipted on same sheet for P.S.DuPonceau. Notice of payment due on books for the library.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 26, 1835; 12x8; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: William John Hamilton. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Peter S. Duponceau, president of A.P.S., Feb. 26, 1835; 6" x 7 3/4"; Grover, Thomas D., 1788-1849
    Southwark, L.S. 1p. and add. (Part of address sheet torn off) On behalf of the Commissioners of Southwark, requests loan of Jefferson and Franklin portraits for the purpose of having copies made by Mr. Etter. Cf. Minutes, March 20, 1835. FILM54-61 FRAME130 FILM 199 FRAME 424
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 27, 1835; 12x8; Netherlands. Ministerie van Binnenlandse Zaken en Landbouw
    The Hague, L.S.: Van Doen. 2p.and end. In Dutch. ----English translation. 1p. Forwards volume. Thanks for APS publication.
  - John Torrey to A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, February 28, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Torrey, John, 1796-1873
    Secretary of the A.P.S., New York, 1 p., address and endorsment. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Report of committee on Torlade d'Azambuja's manuscript on coins of Portugual, Feb., 1835; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Peter S.DuPonceau, Clement C.Biddle and Saml. Moore. 2p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.666.
  - Letter to the secretary of the American philosophical society, March 1, 1835; 8" x 10"; Royal Society of London
    London, L.S: Chas. Konig, For. Sec. R.S. 2p. Contains autographed notation by A.D. Bache. Relative to the medal to be awarded in 1837. Cf. Minutes, May 15, 1835.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, March 5, 1835; 10x8; Royal Society of Edinburgh
  - Letter to W[illia]m Vaughan, March 5, 1835; 9-1/2x8; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    L.S.: Arthur Aikin. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for APS publications.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, March 6, 1835; 10x8; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Peter Clare. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [Peter S.] DuPonceau, Philadelphia, March 12, 1835; 10x8; Morelli, Chevalier Domenico de
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Forwards volume.
  - John Brockenbrough to Ch[arles] D. Meigs, March 16, 1835; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Brockenbrough, John, 1774-1852
    Richmond, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the president of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, March 19, 1835; 14x8; Verulam philosophical society of London
    London, L.S.: H[enry] W[illiam] Dewhurst. 1p. and add. Enc.of prospectus of book by Dewhurst. Asks to begin correspondence with the APS. For enclosure, see: 973: C683, no.160.
  - Report of committee on Mr. Naxera's paper on the Indian languages, March 20, 1835; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Peter S.DuPonceau, Willm. H. Keating, and James P.Espy. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes,p.669. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 249 ff.
  - Treasurer's report concerning insurance, 1835 March 20; American Philosophical Society. Treasurer
    A.P.S. Treasurer reports on insurance, $16,000 on the Library and $4,000 on the Cabinet.
  - Receipt to Tho[ma]s Voigt for cleaning the Rittenhouse clock, April 1, 1835; 3-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    A.D.in hand of J.Vaughan. 1p.and receipted by Tho[ma]s Voigt, end.
  - [Baron de] Ferussac to the Secretary of A.P.S., April 4, 1835; 6 3/8" x 8"; Ferussac, André-Étienne-Just-Paschal-Joseph-François d'Audebard, baron de, 1786-1836
    Paris, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Acknowledges receipt of bill of exchange for 260 fr. Account of use thereof. Exchange of various works.
  - A[lexander] D[allas] Bache to Jno. Vaughan, April 8, 1835; 4 7/8" x 7 3/4"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests loan of Dunglison's Physiology.
  - W[illia]m B. Hodgson to Peter S. DuPonceau, April 10, 1835; 8" x 9 3/4"; Hodgson, William Brown, 1800-1871
    President of the A.P.S., Washington, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents coins from Turkey, Egypt, and Greece to the A.P.S. See Minutes, April 17, 1835, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 670.
  - A list of coins presented to the American Philosophical Society by W[illia]m B. Hodgson, April 10, 1835; 8" x 9 3/4"; Hodgson, William Brown, 1800-1871
    [Washington,]. 3 pp. and endorsement. D. Unsigned. Enclosed in: W[illia]m B. Hodgson to Peter S. Duponceau, April 10, 1835.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 11, 1835; 10x8; Morelli, Chevalier Domenico de
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Forwards donation.
  - Statement of account with the American Philosophical society for telescope, April 13, 1835; 9-1/2x8 and 3x7-1/2; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    A.D.S. 1p.and end.plus statement in J. Vaughan's hand of monies owed P. Vaughan.
  - B. F. Joslin to John Vaughan, April 22, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Joslin, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1796-1861
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. Inquires whether the Society has any record of his description of an air pump, directed to Dr. Hare on October 25, 1823.
  - Catalogue of historical documents in the A.P.S., May 1, 1835; 12x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 5p.and end. Refers to Jefferson and Franklin. Cf. Minutes, p.670. FILM 199 FRAME 675 FILM 54-66 FRAME 110
  - Letter to J. k. Kane, May 7, 1835; 10x8; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Calcutta, L.S.: James Prinsep. 1p. and end. Forwards publication.